Oghogho O. Igodan

3003 Van Ness Street NW • Washington, DC 20008 • (614) 330-1109 • oghoghoigodan@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Public health professional passionate about improving maternal and child health outcomes in the United States and sub-Saharan Africa. Five years of experience managing and implementing donor-funded projects focused on maternal, newborn, and child health, family planning, sexual and reproductive health, and malaria. Demonstrated experience in project management, proposal development, grants and contracts management, strategic planning, and qualitative research. Excellent knowledge of USAID policies, procedures, regulations, and reporting requirements. Experience working with high-level government officials, international organizations, private foundations, ministries of health, and the private sector. Field experience in the Democratic Republic of Congo, Burundi, Uganda, and Tanzania.

EDUCATION

The George Washington University

Master of Public Health in Maternal and Child Health, Cum Laude

May 2018

Washington, DC

Scholarships, Awards and Grants: GW Constance Urciolo Battle, MD, School of Public Health Scholarship, GW Barbara Jackman Zuckert Scholarship, Leopold Schepp Foundation Scholarship, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc. Mary Murphy Graduate Scholarship, P.E.O. Sisterhood Program for Continuing Education Grant, Zeta Phi Beta Sorority, Inc. General Graduate Scholarship, Alpha Kappa Alpha Educational Advancement Foundation Graduate Merit Scholarship, Health Wonk Silver Scholarship, Calvary Foundation Scholarship, Mount Olivet Foundation Grant, Scudder Association Educational Grant, AMCHP Go Beyond MCH Graduate Student Scholarship, GW Shenkman Student Professional and Career Development Grant, GWSPH Capital Connection Fund Award, and Epsilon Sigma Alpha Foundation Career Enhancement Grant.

The Ohio State University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), International Studies, Cum Laude

Minors: French and Women's Studies

June 2011

Columbus, OH

Scholarships, Awards and Honors: 2007-2011 Dean's List, Jack D. and Fredda S. Sparks Scholarship, University Housing All Star Award, Bexley Women's Club College Scholarship, Elsie Mae White Memorial Scholarship.

Université de Bourgogne

CIEF Intensive French Language Program

Summer 2009 Dijon, France

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

United States Agency for International Development (USAID)

GH Pro Consultant - Program Management Advisor

July 2018-Sep 2018 Kinshasa, DRC

- Provided support to the Maternal and Child Health (MCH) Team Lead and Deputy Team Lead in the followup and completion of routine MCH Team activities, such as developing weekly team updates for the DRC Front Office, responding to taskers, ensuring adequate funding for implementing partners, and troubleshooting supply chain issues.
- Provided support to the newly awarded flagship activity Integrated Health Project-DRC, a \$314 million contract awarded to Abt Associates, including assisting with the start-up and the work planning process.
- Assisted with the preparation and finalization of the FY19 DRC Operational Plan. Supported activity managers in drafting the health key issue narrative, implementing mechanism narratives, and budget tables.

• Participated in meetings with donor agencies, the Ministry of Health, and international and local NGOs in support of USAID/DRC goals and objectives.

George Washington University

October 2017-May 2018

Graduate Research Assistant, DC Family Planning Initiative

Washington, DC

- Worked alongside a team of five professors and four graduate research assistants on a family planning needs assessment project.
- Assisted with developing focus group discussion guide; moderating; note-taking; and transcription.
- Conducted 9 focus groups with women and adolescents aged 15-29 living in Washington, DC.
- Conducted thematic content analysis using a comparative coding process to identify salient themes.
- Contributed to the final research report shared with community stakeholders and donors.

Population Council

June 2017-August 2017

Graduate Intern, Maternal and Newborn Health

Washington, DC

- Provided technical support to the Ending Eclampsia and Fistula Care Plus projects.
- Conducted literature searches and retrieved journal articles, contributed to literature reviews for Fistula Care Plus (FC+) studies, reviewed FC+ baseline data and summarized qualitative data, assisted with the development of questionnaires for data collection, and provided writing support for manuscripts.
- Developed communication and advocacy materials, including Ending Eclampsia country profiles, issue briefs, presentations, and infographics.
- Prepared for and participated in meetings with partners (EngenderHealth, Jhpiego) to develop work plans and report on the progress of activities.

United States Agency for International Development (USAID)

March 2016-August 2016

Program Analyst II, President's Malaria Initiative

Washington, DC

Office of Health, Infectious Diseases and Nutrition (HIDN), Bureau for Global Health

- Served as lead Program Analyst in the Malaria Division and the primary point of contact for Malaria Division Chief and Deputy Division Chief.
- Program Management: Supported the Malaria Vaccine Development Program with managing 4 interagency
 agreements. Reviewed, discussed, and consulted with Agreement Officer Representative regarding the
 approval of work plans, budgets, activities, sub-awards, travel plans, and pharmaceutical requests. Provided
 assistance to technical staff and partners to ensure that financial and technical reports are prepared and
 submitted as required.
- Financial and Contract Management: Supported the formulation and implementation of program budgets, including the Malaria Division and Global Health Bureau portfolio review. Worked closely with the HIDN Budget Analyst to ensure the obligation of expiring funds, tracked the status of new fiscal year funding and updated implementing partners on the status of expected funds. Coordinated procurement-related actions and approval requests with the Office of Acquisition and Assistance, including budget realignments, no-cost extensions, financial ceiling increases, and funding modifications. Maintained the malaria section of the Office of Acquisition and Assistance Administrative Tracker.
- Technical Support: Supported core activities of the interagency Malaria in Pregnancy (MiP) Technical Working Group. Liaised with the Jhpiego Malaria Team and USAID Maternal Health Team to ensure coordination of related priorities and activities. Reviewed and provided technical input on training and supervision materials, research proposals, advocacy tools, work plans and concept notes. Served as an alternate supervisor for malaria in pregnancy team interns. Attended and represented PMI at the Roll Back Malaria MIP Working Group annual meeting in Geneva, Switzerland.
- Communication and Collaboration: Responded to inquiries from inside and outside of USAID, including
 from Agency leadership, other USG agencies, development partners, and Congress. Liaised with the Global
 Health Bureau's Administrative Management Staff to address personnel issues. Assisted the PMI
 Communications Team and Retreat Committee with planning the USAID & CDC PMI all-staff retreat in

Lusaka, Zambia. Collaborated with colleagues in the Office of Policy, Programs and Planning regarding financial obligations and reporting requirements.

• Country Experience: Uganda, Burundi (PEPFAR COP), Tanzania.

United States Agency for International Development (USAID)

May 2013-March 2016

Program Assistant and Analyst I, President's Malaria Initiative

Washington, DC

Office of Health, Infectious Diseases and Nutrition (HIDN), Bureau for Global Health

- Prepared various program documents, including action memos, briefers, scheduling requests, amendments and waivers. Organized weekly PMI team meetings, brown bag presentations, and the interagency advisory group meeting.
- Provided executive administrative support to the U.S Global Malaria Coordinator and Deputy Coordinator (political appointees). Assisted with domestic and international travel including reservations and ticketing, hotel accommodations, visa applications, and expense reports. Maintained calendars and scheduled highlevel meetings with government officials and senior executives.
- Participated as a core member of the PMI Commodities, Procurement and Supply Chain Team. Provided programmatic, contractual, and financial support to a multi-country supply chain contract, USAID | DELIVER PROJECT, Malaria Task Order 7. Prepared financial documentation as requested by the Contracting Officer Representative to ensure timely sub-award approvals, budget obligations, and contract modifications. Drafted geographic source code waivers, salary approval letters for Third-Country Nationals, and key personnel requests. Managed the submission and approval of work plan deliverables including data dashboards, country stories, semi-annual and annual reports. Oversaw quarterly financial reporting of the contract and tracked obligations and pipeline. Attended management meetings with implementing partners, PMI technical meetings and program related events.
- Participated as a core member of the PMI Democratic Republic of Congo Headquarters Team. Assisted with
 the annual programming of country malaria operational plans, budgets, and activities. Communicated with
 the in-country team and conducted administrative follow-up by liaising with different technical teams on
 procurement, finance, staffing, and travel. Conducted temporary duty travel in August 2013 and May 2014 to
 Kinshasa and Lubumbashi to evaluate the bottlenecks and challenges related to the supply chain and
 pharmaceutical system and participated in the fiscal year 2015 malaria operational planning visit.
- Haiti Country Team Assistant: Scheduled meetings and presentations, developed briefing materials for highlevel visits, supported program planning activities such as the headquarters and country operational plans and served as control officer for the annual Child Survival Call to Action meeting.
- Reviewed and edited country work plans, program reports and technical materials for the interagency
 Malaria in Pregnancy Technical Working Group. Presented on the revised WHO malaria in pregnancy
 guidelines at the New Info Circuit table session at the CORE Group Spring 2014 Global Health Practitioner
 Conference.
- Country Experience: Democratic Republic of Congo.

World Vision February 2013-May 2013

Program Assistant, Multilateral Donor Engagements and Grants

Washington, DC

- Prepared presentation materials and agendas for quarterly stakeholder meetings, workshops and WebEx calls with World Vision's international offices.
- Drafted and edited the Global Fund business process guides, fact sheets, success stories, and annual reports.
- Designed online surveys to collect data on the effectiveness of World Vision's Global Fund Business Process.
- Maintained the Global Health and WASH page on World Vision's intranet site. Assisted with posting announcements, articles and stories, and uploading files to the document library.

International Medical Corps

October 2012-February 2013

International Operations Intern

Washington, DC

• Provided backstopping support to a \$70 million humanitarian relief and development portfolio in the Great Lakes/West Africa and Latin America/Caribbean region.

- Supported proposal development efforts by conducting desk reviews, landscape analyses, and background research. Drafted and edited technical proposals, updated corporate capability statements, past performance references, and other standard proposal documentation.
- Assisted and managed the recruitment of technical specialists and international consultants. Drafted key personnel requests, teaming agreements, and scopes of work.
- Coordinated with technical teams to compile relevant information for quarterly, semi-annual, and annual reports. Finalized draft donor reports, editing for format, grammar, and content.

Institute for Reproductive Health at Georgetown University

January 2012-July 2012

Capacity Building and Research Intern

Washington, DC

- Supported the design of the Champions of Family Planning Initiative. Specific responsibilities included presenting the project to senior management team, identifying champion individuals, developing interview questionnaire, conducting in-depth interviews with IRH country staff, producing a concept note, work plan, and assembling an electronic packet of resources.
- Managed content on a community-based family planning website for faith-based organizations in Kenya and supported the development of a Standard Days Method Africa Regional toolkit for USAID's Knowledge for Health website.
- Summarized stakeholder analysis reports, edited low-literacy family planning brochures, and performed literature reviews on fertility awareness-based mobile applications.
- Transcribed interviews on gender-sensitive and transformative FAM project activities and conducted qualitative interviews with in-country staff on IRH's use of community health workers.
- Scheduled meetings for the M&E and GREAT teams. Wrote and circulated meeting notes, reviewed and reported action items, and initiated follow-up correspondence.

TransAfrica Forum June 2010-August 2010

Africa Policy and Research Intern

Washington, DC

Internship with TransAfrica Forum through the Ohio State University's Washington Academic Internship Program.

- Created a chronological report on the history of the Democratic Republic of Congo for distribution at the "Congo Independence 50 Years Later: The Continuing Pursuit" event and Cabral/Truth Circle film and book discussion focusing on the legacy of Patrice Lumumba and effects of colonialism.
- Wrote daily news briefs on the economic and political situation in Ethiopia, Nigeria, and DRC and performed historical and legal research for the development of fact sheets and country reports.
- Compiled list of recent book releases and researched topics for TransAfrica's radio show.
- Attended policy meetings and congressional hearings on Capitol Hill.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

U.S. Department of State/IREXFellowship Application Reviewer

February 2014-December 2015

Washington, DC

The Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders is the flagship program of President Obama's Young African Leaders Initiative (YALI). YALI was launched in 2010 to support young African leaders as they work to grow their economies, strengthen democratic institutions and governance, and enhance peace and security across Africa.

• Served on the Reading Committee for the Mandela Washington Fellowship. Reviewed and scored 30 applications for the 2014 and 2015 application cycles.

YoungLives DC January 2014-January 2015

Grant Writer & Volunteer

Washington, DC

YoungLives DC provides pregnant and parenting teens with the tools and resources needed to lead healthy, independent, and productive lives.

• Grant writing and submission of letters of inquiry and proposals to family and private foundations. Tracked potential funding opportunities and maintained database containing information on donors and prospects.

- Led discussions at parenting classes on a wide variety of topics, including sexual health, maintaining healthy relationships, vocational training, and GED preparation.
- Mentored and supported a teen mom and volunteered at the annual walk-a-thon and banquet.

African Cultural and Resource Center

January 2013-March 2013

Peer Health Educator

Silver Spring, MD

The Peer Health Educator Program, made possible through grant funding from the Maryland Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, aims to engage and educate the African immigrant population in Maryland with the knowledge, motivation and skills necessary to reduce their risk of STIs.

- Participated in a training course on sexual and reproductive health, risk reduction, contraceptive methods, HIV-related stigma and discrimination, and implementation of the Enebuluwa HIV Prevention Curriculum.
- Delivered the Enebuluwa HIV Prevention curriculum to groups of up to 30 participants. Led activities, educational games and group discussions on the transmission and prevention of HIV/AIDS and other sexually transmitted infections.
- Assisted in implementation of pre-and post-tests to measure curriculum impact.
- Obtained Peer Health Educator Certificate.

Mary's Center for Maternal and Child Care

June 2012-January 2013

Washington, DC

Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) Program Volunteer

The Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) offers supplemental foods, nutrition education, breastfeeding support, and social service referrals to low-income pregnant, postpartum and breastfeeding women, and infants and children under age five.

- Educated WIC clients about the Farmers' Market Nutrition Program, WIC Breastfeeding Peer Counselors Program, and distributed educational materials to parents and families.
- Worked with nutritionists to take the weight and height measurements of children, issued monthly checks to be used at farmers' markets and/or approved WIC grocery stores and documented check issuance into client log.
- Provided administrative support by greeting and signing in clients, photocopying documents, filing charts, and preparing participant identification folders.

One World Running

March 2011

Special Olympics 5K Fun Run Volunteer

Belize City, Belize

One World Running is an international organization that raises awareness about health, fitness and nutrition and provides running shoes to those in need in the United States and around the world. One World Running partners with the Ohio State University to distribute donated running shoes to Belizeans.

- Volunteered at the annual Special Olympics 5K Fun Run to raise public awareness of disabled and special needs children.
- Registered race participants, assembled packets, distributed t-shirts and race bibs, and provided water to runners and walkers along the course.
- Organized, fitted, and delivered over 1,000 shoes to children and adults of Belize City.